Hello everyone, let's learn how to make silk socks.
Before making silk socks, we need to make it a square state,
so that the grid of the shoes does not affect it.
So we need to delete the shoes.
After deleting the shoes, we need to draw a rectangle.
The width of this rectangle, we will use its knee first,
because the knee is a thinner position,
but it is not as thin as the ankle.
In the process of clicking and dragging the mouse,
make sure its length is from the thinnest position of the waist to the nearest position of the foot.
Press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical plate,
select these two plates, Ctrl C, Ctrl V, and copy them as the back pieces.
Then press Shift F to open the arrangement point,
we arrange the front and back pieces separately,
and arrange them in the corresponding position.
When arranging the plates, we must make sure that all the plates are facing outwards.
Then we need to create a breakpoint in the middle of it.
This breakpoint is where the pants will be sewn together in the cross section,
so we need to make a breakpoint in the middle.
This breakpoint should be located in the lower position of the foot,
because the side of the human body is thick,
so we need to reserve that part of the amount.
Then in the same position of the back piece,
we need to make a breakpoint in the middle of it.
Next, because we can see that the plate is very thin,
if it is directly wrapped around the outside of the virtual model,
it may have some penetration problems.
So we temporarily increase the slope of the plate to 150.
The slope of the tail is only temporarily maintained at 150,
and then we will return it to 100.
Because it is still a relatively narrow position in the 3D window,
in order to prevent penetrations later,
we first add a fixing pin on the four corners.
After adding a fixing pin,
we can start using the line sewing tool.
First, sew the front and middle,
the upper part,
and then the bottom here needs to be sewn back and forth,
just like pants.
Finally, don't forget to sew the sides together.
Then we can start modeling.
After opening the simulation,
we can see that there is a very heavy fixing pin.
As long as there are no obvious wear and tear problems,
we can delete all the fixing pins.
Now we will see that there are some breakpoints in the version.
The problem with this breakpoint is that it was previously reduced by the surface diameter,
so if the particle diameter is too large,
it looks like there will be a breakpoint.
If we reduce the particle diameter to 10,
its breakpoint problem can be solved very well.
After that, we will see that the overall position of it is a little low.
Then we can press Alt 4,
open the transparency chart,
and look at the position of its breakpoint.
Now we will see that its breakpoint position is relatively low,
so we can select the straight line point of the breakpoint.
Note that we need to use the edit panel tool
to select the straight line point of the breakpoint,
and lift it up a little bit.
Note that at the same time,
select the point of the breakpoint on all panels,
and lift it up a little bit.
After that,
we need to reduce the strength of the tail gauze,
as well as the strength of the toe line,
because in real life,
Siwa is very flexible,
so its stretch performance must be very good.
When the strength of the tail gauze is relatively low,
the stretch performance is relatively good.
If there is still a problem,
we can pull it up a little bit.
The reason why it keeps falling down
is because it is too tight now,
and the entire pants will move in a non-tight direction,
so it will move down to the knee position.
Therefore,
it is very important to reduce the strength of the tail gauze of the fabric.
You can even reduce its strength to 1,
including the strength of its toe line.
After that,
we will find that
when we start the simulation
and drag the panel,
it will be much easier to drag than before.
Because Siwa itself
is a very close-knit structure,
so we are now going to reduce the conflict density of Siwa
from 2.5 to 1,
to reduce the air density between it and the virtual model.
If there is still a slight crack now,
we can reduce its overall particle diameter to 8,
and then simulate it again.
The conflict density here is red,
which means that
the conflict density of several panels in the middle
has not been reduced before.
Now,
we can reduce the conflict density of all Siwa panels to 1,
and then simulate it again.
Now,
we can see that
if we turn on the transparency display,
it is now in a relatively close state overall.
Next,
we will start to make the foot of Siwa.
First,
we right-click in the 3D background,
and select the simulation property.
In the simulation property,
we turn off the conflict on the ground,
because later,
if we drag the socks,
it may have some conflicts with the ground.
Next,
we turn on the simulation,
and we can pass the panels through the soles.
If we find that the soles of the feet
or the soles of the fabric
have a gap,
causing the fabric to be difficult to drag,
we can select all panels,
and then harden them.
After the panels are hardened,
the properties will become harder,
and it is not easy to bend,
so it is not easy to be hooked by the grid of the soles.
Next,
we will use the 3D drawing tool
to draw a curve close to the soles of the feet
to make it easier for us to sew later.
Here,
when we use the 3D drawing tool,
we have to pay attention to
reserve a little space for the soles of the feet.
Because we have used the horizontal and vertical shrink rate
of this panel,
we have to use the internal line tool
to draw a pattern that fits our feet.
In the process of drawing,
it is best to keep a straight line point,
so that it is convenient for us to adjust later.
Do not create a curve point for all of them,
and then copy and paste it on the back.
Then select these internal lines,
right-click and select Cut,
and then delete the excess part.
After cutting the panel,
the hardening used in the original will be automatically removed,
and the panel will be softened.
If it is not automatically removed,
right-click and select Cancel Hardening.
Now,
we switch back to the thick texture surface.
When the panel is softened,
we will see that
in fact,
this panel is now a little longer.
So we have to follow its original direction,
pull these bottom lines up a little bit,
shorten the length of the soles of the feet.
When we look at the 3D window,
we can see that
this panel is just above the soles of the feet.
If the soles of the feet are quite different from the panel,
we can increase the curve intensity first
to prevent the panel from being different from the soles of the feet.
Then,
we manually pull this panel out a little bit.
As for the soles of the feet,
in order to prevent it from being unstable later,
we can use a fixed needle
to move the two panels a little closer.
Then,
we create the sewing line again.
When moving the fixed needle,
please note that
you must activate the simulation
so that the panel can move together with your adjustment.
If you pause the simulation,
it will move in an instant.
Next,
we can use the sewing tool to sew the two sides together.
Then,
we can delete the fixed needle.
If there is still a problem with the soles of the feet,
we can manually adjust it a little bit.
If there is no way to avoid the insertion problem,
then we continue to reduce the soles of the feet from 8 to 5.
Generally speaking,
these problems can be solved.
Now,
we will find that the overall curve intensity is relatively large.
Since we have reduced the soles of the feet
and there are no more penetrating problems,
we can reduce the curve intensity a little bit.
Then,
because this pair of socks will become very tight later,
in order to prevent it from falling down due to tightness,
we need to increase its friction coefficient first.
Then,
we can try to pull its waist up a little bit.
If its length is not enough,
we can give it a little longer.
Next,
we will return the shrinkage rate from 150 to 100.
First of all,
in the case of choosing all the pieces,
reduce the waist shrinkage rate from 150 to 130.
Then,
reduce it from 130 to 120.
Every time it is reduced,
we have to re-calculate it.
During the calculation process,
if we find that the pants move down,
it doesn't matter.
We will continue to adjust it later.
Next,
we will reduce the waist shrinkage rate from 120 to 110.
At this time,
the whole strain of the socks is very tight.
If we find it moving,
we need to slung the panel slung
in time so that it doesn't move.
Next,
we can gradually reduce its waist shrinkage rate from 130 to 190.
If it is not enough,
we can reduce it to 90.
If there are any small creases after the tail is reduced to 90 degrees, we will manually adjust its position by pressing Alt 4 to open the transparency picture.
If we find that its bending strength is relatively high, which causes it to be in a position where the ankle can not be tightly attached to the ankle,
we can reduce its bending strength by a little bit.
However, if the bending strength is relatively low, the ankle may still have penetrating problems, so try to adjust it little by little.
If we still need to tighten it at this time, we can continue to reduce its bending strength by 80%.
However, if the bending strength is reduced to 80%, its thigh position will definitely become very serious.
So in addition to changing the bending strength of the tail, we can also choose all the plates to give them a negative pressure.
Through the negative pressure, we can make the plate receive a fixed force from the outside to the inside,
so that the plate is tightly wrapped outside the virtual model.
After we adjust it, we can start to deal with the problem of the foot.
First of all, it is actually similar to the previous adjustment.
We choose the point of the foot.
In the case of the front and back pieces being selected at the same time, move this point up a little bit.
Because now we have given it a fixed negative pressure, plus it has friction coefficient,
so now we are adjusting it.
Although it is very tight, it will not move down again.
After the foot is determined, we will pull the upper part of the plate up a little bit,
so that it reaches the position of the waist.
If you feel that it is not tight enough now,
you can pull this point up a little bit.
After that, the upper left corner is saved as a clothing file.
Then we open the file of the rabbit girl clothes and models that we have saved before.
Choose to open the clothing.
You have to choose to increase the loading type, otherwise the clothes will be replaced.
After increasing, because we were wearing sports shoes before,
now we delete the shoes first.
Then arrange the new socks version in the 2D window.
Then freeze the socks version in the 3D space.
Then select all the top 1 versions and set their levels to 1.
Then open the simulation.
After opening the simulation, the clothes will automatically be worn outside the four socks.
After the simulation is stable, return the level to 0.
Then we freeze all the top 1 versions.
Then freeze the socks version and simulate it.
In this way, we can activate all the versions
under the condition that both inside and outside layers must be stable,
and then simulate them together.
Then open the left corner,
open the position in the Baidu network plate on our belly,
cancel the hook,
and choose to keep the current shoes position.
Because this action is an action in the state of high heel shoes.
The previous virtual model was wearing sneakers.
After we change the position,
consider that the shoes may have a conflict with the sheets later.
So we can reduce the conflict thickness of all the sheets to 0.
Try to reduce the air thickness near it.
Because the virtual model now has the surface diameter of 1.
We can't reduce it anymore.
If we reduce it, the sheets and the human body are too close together.
It may be unstable.
Adjust the socks version manually.
Try not to have an intersection with the toes.
Then we go to the library.
In the HANA file folder,
double click to import high heel shoes.
After importing high heel shoes, the heel will automatically go up.
So here we choose the virtual model.
Right click, choose to adjust the heel to the bottom.
Let its heel return to the original correct position.
If there are other versions of creation or adjustment later,
please try to avoid the interaction of socks and shoes.
If you must interact, please add a fixer.
This video is over here.
See you next time, bye.